《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
昨晚  有个疯子冻住了一名警察  造成死亡
Last night, some psycho froze a cop to death.
他用的是过冷液态氦
He was using supercooled liquid helium.
那是世界上可以最高效地
It's one of the most effective substances in the world
进行急速降温的化学物质
for rapid temperature reduction.
他只是想知道来源
He just wants to know where it comes from
我们好顺藤摸瓜找出那个人
so we can track down the guy
你承认杀人了
You confess to murder?
是的  我承认
Yes, I do.
要知道  我不是罪犯
I'm not a criminal, you know?
我是个...疯子
I'm just... insane.
我差点做了过界的事  是吧
I almost crossed the line, didn't I?
真不像你
How out of character.
我有点吓到了
Scared me a little.
我早就吓到了
Welcome to my world.
正如计划的那样  我可以冷冻你
I can freeze you, like we planned.
-但是  -我无法让你复活
- But? - I can't bring you back.
A41号溶液
Solution A14.
不不不不不
No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
只是想到被你拿来试验的可怜的小老鼠
I'm just thinking of all those poor mice you're experimenting on.
你现在打算怎么办
What are you gonna do now?
自己去找这个马龙
Look for this Malone guy yourself?
老实说  我还没想那么远呢
Honestly, I haven't thought that far ahead.
诺拉
Nora.
你要帮我救我妻子
You are going to help save my wife.
我丈夫做了可怕的事
My husband did terrible things.
但他是为我才做了那些可怕的事
But he did those terrible things for my sake.
我要死了
I'm dying.
他想救我
He wants to save me.
我想认罪
I'd like to make a confession.
是我在到处冻人
I'm the man that's been freezing people.
A16  成功了
A16. It worked.
我死了吗
Am I dead?
居然成功了
I can't believe it worked.
我就来  诺拉
I'm coming for you, Nora.
我这就来救你
I'm coming to save you.
本字幕由ZiMuZu原创翻译  最新下载请登录www.ZiMuZu.tv
翻译 辰星晓Reginamoon   小胖纸Amy   Silence  charcie
翻译 大K   小酸奶!   木浅    草草   后期 饿得慌
时间轴 风吹来的那片云   校对&总监 草草
人都哪去了
Where is everybody?
听好了
Listen up.
王牌化工制造液态氦
Ace Chemicals makes the liquid helium
维克多·弗莱斯用其为他的武器供能
Victor Fries uses to power his weaponry.
弗莱斯被发现于20分钟前进入这栋楼
Fries was spotted entering the building 20 minutes ago.
他不顾死活
He's desperate
并且极度危险
and extremely dangerous.
开始行动吧
Let's do this.
王牌化工
韦恩集团下属部门
我去
Damn.
这里到底发生了什么
What the hell happened here?
夜班门卫
Night janitor.
可能是个人质
Could be a hostage.
警探
Detectives.
几个罐子没了
Canisters gone.
看来他得到他想找的了
Looks like he got what he was after.
他想干什么
What's he planning?
释放我妻子
"释放我妻子"
"Free my wife."
哥谭
第二季  第十三集
瑞士之行怎么样
How was Switzerland?
那里有山  有雪
They have mountains, snow.
大家都很礼貌
People are polite.
阿尔弗雷德说你想和我谈谈
Alfred said you wanted to talk to me.
阿尔弗雷德想让我和你谈谈
Alfred wanted me to speak with you.
他很担心你
He's worried about you.
他担心你可能在隐瞒
He's worried that you might be concealing
自己心理上的创伤
any trauma you must be feeling.
他不必担心
He needn't worry.
我告诉他我没事  我的确没事
I tell him I'm fine, which I am,
但他不相信我
and he doesn't believe me.
你遭受了粗暴的绑架  还差点没命了
You were violently abducted. You nearly died.
你一定害怕极了
You must have been very scared.
感到受创是很正常的
It's normal to feel trauma.
你没必要为此羞愧
It's nothing you need to be ashamed of.
我没觉得害怕
I wasn't scared.
没有吗
No?
那你是什么感受
What did you feel?
我觉得振奋
I felt alive.
非常有活力
Intensely alive.
你觉得我不正常吗
Do you think I'm abnormal?
绝对是与众不同
You're certainly unusual,
假如你说的是实话
if you're being honest.
我一向诚实
I'm always honest.
那很好啊
That's a good way to be.
很难做到
Tough to pull off.
我尽力为之
I try.
那你现在是什么感受呢
And how do you feel now?
正如我说的  我感觉...没事
As I say, I feel... fine.
精力充沛
Invigorated.
我获得了第二次生活的机会
I have a second chance at life.
那你打算如何利用这机会呢
What do you plan to do with that chance?
我的计划依然如故
My plans remain unchanged.
找到杀害我父母的那个人
Find the man who killed my parents.
布鲁斯  你需要了结
Bruce, you need closure.
没错
Exactly.
是了结
Closure.
不是危险地
Not a dangerous
并且可能是无休无止地执迷于此
and possibly endless obsession.
我会找到他的
I'll find him.
你是个小男孩  不是凶案组警探
You're a schoolboy, not a homicide detective.
我相信人可以同时拥有两个身份
I believe people can be two things at once,
你不觉得吗
don't you think so?
没错  的确可以
Yes, they can.
就算你找到了那个罪犯  然后呢
So, you find the culprit, what then?
我会让法律制裁他
I'll let the law take its course.
这是诚实的回答吗
Is that the truthful answer?
这是我给你回答
It's the answer I'm giving you.
一向诚实的布鲁斯呢
What happened to Honest Bruce?
这是个好问题
That's a very good question.
那大概是另一个布鲁斯吧
I guess that's the other Bruce.
抱歉  我无意对你无礼
Sorry, I don't mean to be flippant with you.
这次谈话对我很有帮助
This conversation has been very useful.
让我想通很多
Clarifying.
或许我们可以找时间再谈一次
Perhaps we can do it again sometime.
当然  可以
Sure, we can do that.
"释放我妻子"
"Free my wife"?!
这家伙杀了七个警察
This guy thinks by killing seven cops,
还指望我们释放他妻子吗
he can get us to free his wife?!
我一脚踩死这该死的冻人
I'll free my boot up his frozen ass!
臭疯子  狗娘养的  我要撕了他
Tin can lunatic, son of a bitch, I'll tear his...
我要缓口气
I'm going to take a breath.
人质怎么样了  那个门卫  有提什么要求吗
What about this hostage-- the janitor-- any demands?
还没有
Not yet.
显然  我们是在对付一个疯子
Obviously, we're dealing with a madman,
一旦他意识到我们不会放了他妻子
and once he realizes that we're not going to release his wife,
他就会来找我们
he's going to come to us,
想办法救她出去  对吗
try to get her, right?
要不还能怎样
What else would he do?
我想也是
I guess.
等他来时  我们会做好准备的
When he does, we'll be ready for him,
然后抓住他
and we'll take him.
-她现在在哪里  -在拘留室里
- Where is she now? - In a holding cell.
小莱和一个护理人员在照看她
Lee and a paramedic are seeing to her.
小莱说如果不尽快转移她去医院
Lee says if she doesn't move to a hospital soon,
她会死的
she could die.
该死
Damn it.
我们保证不了哥谭总院的安全
We can't secure Gotham General.
那里入口太多了  还有太多平民
There's too many access points, too many civilians.
阿卡姆
Arkham.
那里有个设施完善的急诊室  对吗
They have a full ER facility, right?
我们带她去阿卡姆
We'll take her to Arkham.
这样她就能得到她所需要的医疗
This way she can get the care that she needs,
我们也能在不危及平民的前提下抓到弗莱斯
and we can capture Fries without endangering any civilians.
有道理
Makes sense.
有道理吗
Sense?
那可是个疯人院
It's a lunatic asylum,
里面全是疯子
filled with crazy people.
那你有更好的主意吗
You got any better ideas?
没有
N-No.
你为她做准备
You prep her to travel.
我去打给阿卡姆的院长
I'll call the director at Arkham.
把消息放给媒体
And get that out to press.
我要弗莱斯上钩
I want Fries taking the bait.
你去告诉小莱
I'm going to let you tell Lee
我们要把她的病人带去疯人院吧
that we're taking her patient to the nut house.
她会理解的
She'll understand.
当然  完全理解
Oh, yeah, totally, completely.
让我搞清楚
Let me get this straight.
你们打算利用一个奄奄一息的女人作诱饵
You plan on using a dying woman as bait.
拴在阿卡姆作诱饵
A tethered goat at Arkham.
不是这样的
It's not like that.
你打算告诉她丈夫你们要带她去哪吗
Are you going to tell her husband where you're taking her?
-是的  但是...  -那就是这样
- Yes, but... - Then it is like that.
这是几个糟糕选项中最好的了
It's the least bad of several bad options.
我们可以传播假消息  说她在哥谭总院
We could spread false word that she's at Gotham General,
但如果弗莱斯袭击那里呢
but what happens when Fries attacks?
那里到处是病重患者  无法移动
It's filled with people who are too sick to move.
这个办法很合理
This is the rational way to go.
有时合理的办法不一定最好
Sometimes the rational way is not the best way.
如果有更好的办法  我们愿意一试
If there were a better way, we would take it.
相信我  诺拉·弗莱斯会非常安全
Trust me, Nora Fries will be perfectly safe.
我要走了
I-I got to go.
我跟她一起去
I'm going with her.
小莱  阿卡姆有医生
Lee, there are doctors at Arkham.
她是我的病人
She's my patient.
我在那儿工作过  我了解那些医生  我要去
I used to work there, I know those doctors. I'm going.
这样不安全
It's not safe.
诺拉在那儿安全  可我去就不安全了吗
It's safe for Nora, but it's not safe for me?
不  别这样
No, now, now, now, look...
再想想吧  帅哥  我去拿我的东西
Yeah, keep thinking, hotshot, I'm going to get my stuff.
不  你知道我的意思
No, you know what I meant.
如果你用孩子做挡箭牌  我就要大叫了
If you use this on me, I'm going to scream.
那是谁
Who was that?
弗莱斯冻住的一个人
One of Fries's victims.
我本希望能从此人的身体组织里
I'd hoped to extract traces of Fries's formula
提取弗莱斯的溶液  可惜不走运
from the man's tissue, but no such luck.
话说  有人打电话找你
Speaking of, you had a call.
哥谭市警局想把诺拉·弗莱斯
The GCPD wants to transfer Nora Fries
送去阿卡姆的医疗区
to Arkham medical wing.
你是说他的妻子
You mean the wife?
看来她病得很重
Apparently, she's very sick.
警方认为弗莱斯也许会企图劫囚
The police think Fries may try to break her out.
他们需要戒备更森严的医疗机构
They need a more secure medical location.
弗莱斯这么做肯定都是为了救他妻子
Fries must be doing all this to save his wife.
真浪漫
How romantic.
太完美了
How perfect.
我正急需他的人体冷冻专业知识呢
Here I am desperately in need of his cryonic expertise,
而他就要送上门了
and he's going to make a house call.
命运垂青于我们啊
The fates are smiling on us.
快  皮博迪  我们得做准备
Swiftly, Peabody, we must prepare.
...从冷冻中恢复过来
...having recovered from being frozen solid,
然后跌跌撞撞地走到困惑不解的哥谭市警局面前
before stumbling out, to the bewilderment of the GCPD.
他被送去了哥谭纪念医院
He was taken to Gotham Memorial,
在那里他的轻伤得到了治疗  随后出院
where he was treated for minor injuries and released.
我们刚刚收到消息
We are now getting word
恶名昭彰的急冻人先生之妻  诺拉·弗莱斯
that Nora Fries, wife of the infamous Mr. Freeze,
将要被送至阿卡姆疯人院的医疗区
is being taken to the medical wing of Arkham Asylum...
阿卡姆
Arkham?
她该待在医院里  不是跟疯子关在一起
She belongs in a hospital, not thrown in among lunatics.
警方没有正式提出指控
...there have been no official charges...
这是个陷阱
It's a trap.
当然了
Of course it is.
他们要利用她来抓我
They're using her to get to me.
这群蠢蛋
The fools.
以为墙壁和枪就能拦得住我吗
They think walls and guns can stop me?
简直无知
They have no idea.
他们会学乖的
They'll learn.
放开我  你们这些野蛮人
Let me go, you brutes!
我要见斯特兰奇教授
I want to speak to Professor Strange.
斯特兰奇主管今天很忙
Director Strange is very busy today.
但是请放心
But rest assured,
阿卡姆的一切
nothing happens at Arkham
都是在他授意下进行的
not according to his wishes.
这是什么东西
What is this thing?
你们要对我做什么
What are you doing to me?
你将成为我们康复项目的招牌
You are to be the face of our rehabilitation program.
如果连奥斯瓦尔德·科波特都能治好
If we can cure a man like Oswald Cobblepot,
那我们就能治愈任何人
we can cure anyone.
我拒绝
I refuse.
我拒绝加入你们的项目
I refuse to be part of your program.
你没有选择
You have no choice.
告诉你  女人
Know this, woman.
所有惹恼了企鹅的人都追悔莫及
Nobody yet has failed to regret vexing the Penguin.
而你正在惹恼我
And you are vexing me!
你最好想清楚自己在做什么
Make your next decision very carefully.
鸭子
Duck.
Duck...
鸭子
Duck.
Duck!
感谢上帝
Thank God.
-只是个梦  -鸭子
- It was only a dream. - Duck.
只是个梦啊
It was only a dream.
鹅
Goose!
你该来追我的
You're supposed to chase me.
你是鹅
You're the goose.
不  我是
No. No. I-I'm, uh...
我是
I'm the...
我是企鹅
I'm-I'm a penguin.
鹅
Goose!
鹅  鹅
Goose! Goose!
有问题吗
Problem?
他不当鹅
He's not being the goose.
参与小组活动很好玩的  科波特先生
It's fun to participate in group, Mr. Cobblepot.
你该尝试一下
You should try.
好
Yes.
好的  我很乐意
Yes. I-I... I'd be glad to.
他们要我做什么
What is it they want me to do?
当鹅
Be the goose.
好的
Okay.
天哪  那是企鹅吗
Sweet mother. Is that Penguin?
鸭子
Duck.
好像被下了药
He seems drugged.
他来这里后情绪一直很焦躁
He's been quite agitated since he arrived.
我们用了轻度镇静剂  以免他伤害自己
We put him on a mild sedative to keep him from hurting himself.
汤普金斯医生  我的助手
Dr. Thompkins, my assistant,
皮博迪女士  她会带你去医务室
Ms. Peabody, will accompany you to the infirmary.
有什么需要她都会帮你
She can provide whatever you need.
谢谢
Thank you.
鸭子
Duck.
Duck...
我们会在大门蹲守
We'll set up by the main gate.
最好让犯人都回自己的囚室
You should probably get the inmates back in their cells.
鸭子
Duck...
Duck.
-鸭子  -哈维  走了
- Duck. - Harv, come on.
鸭子
Duck.
Duck...
鸭子
我想你不会介意和基恩小姐共用一间吧
I trust you won't mind sharing the wing with our dear Ms. Kean.
你开玩笑吧
You've got to be kidding me.
你认识睡美人啊  这是我起的外号
Oh, do you know Sleeping Beauty? That's my name for her.
多美多安静
So lovely, so still.
天使一样
Like an angel.
有问题吗
Is there a problem?
没  完全没问题
No. No problem at all.
平克尼  设置障碍
Pinkney, I want obstacles set up
阻止弗莱斯进入主楼
to keep Fries from entering the main building.
-是  长官  -用大巴吧
- Yes, sir. - What about the bus?
行  好主意
Yeah. Good idea.
哈维  找个狙击手上楼顶待命
And Harvey, I want a shooter up on that roof.
吉姆  吉姆
Jim! Jim!
吉姆  老朋友  吉姆
Jim, my old friend! Jim!
救命  求你
Help, please!
等一下
Wait!
等等
Wait.
给我俩点时间
Give us a minute.
谢天谢地你来了
Thank God you're here.
你得帮我
You have to help me.
他们在虐待我
They're torturing me.
向来都是你虐待别人
Torture is what you do.
这儿的医生是在帮你
The doctors here are trying to help you.
是虐待  相信我
It's torture, I'm telling you!
我没看见你有创伤
I don't see any signs of it.
是精神虐待
It's mental torture.
那是治疗
It's therapy.
你是疯子  记得吗
You're insane, remember?
反正你的律师是这么说的
That's what your lawyers said, anyhow.
再见  企鹅
Good-bye, Penguin.
你欠我的  吉姆·戈登  我为你撒了谎
You owe me, Jim Gordon. I lied for you!
是他杀了盖勒文  不是我  是他
He killed Galavan! Not me! It was him!
是他  医生
It was him, Doc!
你欠我的  吉姆·戈登  我为你撒了谎
You owe me, Jim Gordon. I lied for you!
是他杀了盖勒文  不是我  是他
He killed Galavan! Not me! It was him!
是他  医生
It was him, Doc!
是他
It was him!
他应该已经吸取教训了  布鲁斯少爷
I'd say that's learned him, Master Bruce.
我们本该进行训练的
We were supposed to have a training session.
我在城里有事耽搁了
Yeah, well, I got held up in the city, didn't I?
而且  我以为你跟汤普金斯医生的谈话
Besides, I thought your chat with Dr. Thompkins
会让你无暇顾他
would keep you occupied.
我以为你反对心理咨询呢
And I thought you were against therapy.
那是在我发现你那么喜欢隐瞒秘密之前
Well, that's before I realized you're so keen on keeping secrets.
如果我告诉你塞琳娜和我的计划
If I had told you what Selina and I had planned,
你会阻止我的
you would have stopped me.
就因为没告诉你
Because I didn't,
才从茜尔薇那儿得知了杀我父母凶手的名字
I got the name of my parents' killer from Silver.
然后你带我离开哥谭
Then you made us leave Gotham.
浪费了一个多月的时间
We lost more than a month
本来可以用来找M·马龙的
we could've spent searching for M. Malone.
我们离开这里
We left the city 'cause
是因为你的情绪和身体状态几近崩溃
you were at the end of your emotional and your physical rope--
实话说
and quite frankly,
你连小感冒都得不了  别说抓凶手了
you're incapable of catching a common cold, let alone a killer.
能停下不
Wil... Will you stop?!
我得问你个重要的问题
Now, I need to ask you a very important question:
你我是否
Are we in this together...
是一条心
...or not?
是
Yes.
你我一条心
We're in this together.
好  我跟你说我在城里办了点事
Right. Well, I told you I had some business in the city.
去见了位认识的警员
Went to see a sergeant that I know,
我俩查了哥谭市警局的档案
and we did some digging in some GCP files for any
寻找符合描述的M马龙
M. Malones that fit our particulars.
包括年龄  体格  身高  种族
Age, size, height, race,
你父母被杀期间是否在押
whether they were free during the murder of your parents.
然后呢
And?
帕特里克·马龙
Patrick Malone.
绰号为...
Goes by the nickname...
"火柴"
Matches.
很有趣的人
Delightful chap, really.
15岁时犯下第一桩杀人案
Committed his first murder when he was 15.
之后涉嫌六起杀人案
Suspected of half a dozen since.
我现在要问你
Now, I need to ask you,
如果由你说了算
if you were in charge,
下一步怎么走
what next?
从戈登警探那里也能打听到这些信息
You could've got this information from Detective Gordon.
你为什么没联系他
Why didn't you contact him?
是我在问问题  布鲁斯少爷
I'm the one asking questions now, Master Bruce.
我们找到这个人
We find this man...
你打算怎么做
...what do you plan to do?
杀了他
Kill him.
不行
No.
你阻止不了我
You can't stop me.
我能阻止  也一定会阻止
I bloody can and I will.
你还这么小
You're too young to have
不能就此背上条人命  布鲁斯少爷
a death on your conscience, Master Bruce.
-但  -我知道应为你父母讨回公道
- But, but... - I know how your parents deserve justice.
我知道不报此仇  你不会罢休
I know you're not gonna stop till you find it.
但等我们找到这个马龙
But when we find this Malone,
我来杀他  你不能动手
I will kill him and not you.
必须如此
That is the deal.
你接受吗
Do you accept?
好
Yes.
说出来
Say it.
我们找到他
We find him,
让他供认罪行
we make him talk,
你来杀了他
you kill him.
你都不知道自己错过了多少好戏
You have no idea what you're missing.
贱人
Bitch.
我在哪里
Where am I?
诺拉  好好躺着
Nora, try not to exert yourself.
-你在医院  -你是谁
- You're in a hospital. - Who are you?
这里不是哥谭总院
This is not Gotham General.
确实不是  这里更安全
No. You're in a... more secure place.
我是汤普金斯医生
I'm Dr. Thompkins.
叫我小莱吧
Lee.
他们害怕维克多
They're scared of Victor.
是的
Yes.
维克多做这么多坏事都是为了我
Victor only did these terrible things because of me.
你丈夫的行为  你不必自责
You're not responsible for your husband's actions.
他不是个坏人
He's not an evil man.
他认为只要能救我
He believes the good of saving me
他作恶也值得
outweighs the bad of his actions.
我懂
I understand.
但我现在关心的人不是他  而是你
But he's not my concern right now-- you are.
你要保持冷静  你病情稳定了
And you have to try and stay calm. You're stable
但你还是很虚弱
but you're still very fragile.
我本能救他的
I could have saved him.
我眼睁睁看着他走上歪道
I saw him going down this path.
越来越走火入魔
Becoming more and more obsessed.
我之前为什么没做点什么
Why didn't I do something?
我理解你的意思
I know what you mean.
爱一个人很艰难
It's hard, when you love someone.
你能看到他曾经的样子
You see the person that they were,
他依然可以成为的那个人
the person they could still become.
你对真相视而不见
You close your eyes to the truth.
他要来找我了  对吗
He's coming for me, isn't he?
警方是这么认为的
The police think so.
我的维克多  真是固执
So stubborn, my Victor.
你怀孕了吗
You're pregnant?
是的
Yes.
知道是女孩还是男孩了吗
Do you know yet if it's a boy or girl?
还不知道
Not yet.
我一直想要个女孩
I always wanted a girl.
你不该待在这里
You shouldn't be here.
我们要关心的是你
Let's focus on you
别担心我了  好吗
and not worry about me, okay?
大冬天的监视一个疯人院
Winter stakeout at the loony bin.
太棒了
Fabulous.
诺拉没多少时间了  弗莱斯知道
Nora doesn't have long. Fries knows that.
-他很快就会来的  -最好如此
- He'll come soon. - He'd better.
我们等在这里会冻死的
We could freeze to death, waiting.
那就很讽刺了
Which would be ironic.
你听到了吗
You hear that?
找好掩护
Take cover!
-注意  注意  -注意
- Heads up! Heads up! - Heads up!
开火
Open fire!
上  上  打开车门
Go, go! Get the door!
打开车门
Get the door!
把手举起来
Hands in the air!
我做不到
I can't. I can't.
别开枪
Don't shoot!
维克多·弗莱斯在哪
Where's Victor Fries?
我不知道
I don't know!
拜托  帮帮我
Please, help me!
我们走  快点
Let's go. Come on.
走  快进去
Go on. Go. Go in.
-有几个...  -妈妈
- There's a few... - Mommy?
妈妈
Mommy?
妈...妈
Mom... my...
妈妈
Mommy!
妈
Mom?
收到
Copy that.
弗莱斯击碎了东区的一座墙
Fries took out a wall in the east wing.
让B队截住他
Have B Team cut him off.
我们直接去医务室
We'll head directly to the infirmary.
A队呼叫B队  继续追捕嫌犯
Alpha to Bravo, continue pursuing suspect.
我们正在前往医务室
We're headed to the infirmary.
收到
Copy that.
继续追捕
Maintain pursue.
寻找掩护
Take cover!
诺拉
Nora!
搞什么
What the hell?
快去
Go!
你好  维克多
Hello, Victor.
不好意思  我就开门见山了
Forgive me for getting straight to the point.
我非常崇拜你的杰作
I'm a great admirer of your work
我想帮助你走出当前的困境
and I would like to offer you a way out of your situation.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是个朋友  但我问问你
I'm a friend, but let me ask you:
你救出你妻子后
once you rescue your wife,
有什么打算
what is your plan?
偷一辆车
To steal a vehicle?
一路炸出去
Blast your way out?
椅子上有一串钥匙
There is a set of keys on the chair.
与钥匙对应的车就停在装卸区等着
They belong to a vehicle that is waiting by the loading docks.
我怎么知道这不是陷阱
How do I know it's not a trap?
不是陷阱
It is not a trap,
而是交换
it is an exchange.
你可以得到你妻子和自由
You get your wife and your freedom--
我可以控制住警察  让你逃跑
I can keep the police at bay while you escape.
作为感谢  你要留下
As thanks, you will leave me
一罐冷冻液给我
one cartridge of your cryonic formula.
怎么样
What do you say?
警察要来了
The police are coming,
你不可能把他们都击败
you can't beat them all
而且你的时间不多了
and time is running out for you...
诺拉也是
and for Nora.
去拿来  好吗  皮博迪女士
Go fetch that, would you, Ms. Peabody?
弗莱斯就在楼里
Fries is in the building.
我们得走了
We have to go.
我们不能丢下她
We can't leave her.
警报一响这里的员工就跑了
The staff bailed when the alarm went off.
她会死的
She'll die.
那就把她也带上
So we take her with us.
走吧
Come on.
小心
Careful.
谢谢
Thank you.
交给我吧
I'll take it from here.
维克多  维克多  听我说
Victor... Victor, listen to me.
我们是想帮她
We're trying to help her.
你们要害死她了
You're killing her.
-不  维克多  -维克多
- No. No, Victor. - Victor...
我理解你这么做的原因
I understand why you're doing this.
我要救她的命
I'm saving her life.
你为此要害死多少其他人
At the cost of how many other lives?
已经太多  现在无法回头了
Too many to turn back now.
等我做完了我该做的
Soon as I've done what I need to do,
我就会自首
I'll give myself up.
但现在  我们得走了
But now we have to leave.
维克多  我是名医生
Victor, I'm a doctor.
我们现在转移她  她可能会死
If we move her now, she might die.
医生  太好了
A doctor. Good.
你跟我们一起走  给她推轮椅  走吧
You're coming with us to push the wheelchair. Let's go.
绝对不行
No. No way!
吉姆  我要去
Jim, I'm going.
她是我的病人
She's my patient.
我不能让你那么做  我跟你走
I can't let you do that. I'll go.
-带我走吧  -吉姆  这你说了不算
- Take me. - Jim, it's not your call.
她需要我
She needs me.
我不会伤害她的
I'm not gonna hurt her.
我并不想伤害谁
I don't want to hurt anyone,
除非别无选择
unless I have to.
吉姆  我要去
Jim, I'm going.
维克多  求你
Victor, please...
别这样
don't do this.
诺拉  别担心
Nora, don't worry.
我有把握
It's all under control.
救命
Help...
我们得走了  快点
We have to go. Now.
你  进去
You. In there.
听他的
Do what he's saying.
我们不会有事的
We'll be okay.
快点
Now!
好吧
Okay.
好了  我们走
Okay, let's go.
太感谢了
Thank you so much.
小莱
Lee!
抱歉  警官们
Apologies, officers.
极度低温让电线短路了
The extreme cold has shorted the wiring.
我们还在检修
We're working on it.
那就快点
Well, work on it quick!
我们在做了
Oh, we are.
在做了
We are.
把那个妥善保管
Please put that somewhere very safe,
好吗  皮博迪女士
would you, Ms. Peabody?
好消息  警官们
Good news, officers.
弗莱斯提到
Did Fries say anything,
他的计划了吗
anything at all about his plans?
没有
No, nothing.
他只说"抱歉"
He just said "Sorry."
搭档
Partner!
我们错过了什么
What'd we miss?
弗莱斯带走了诺拉和小莱
Fries got away with Nora and Lee.
我全境通告了车辆  但没被别的线索了
I put a BOLO out on the vehicle, but that's all we got.
弗莱斯得尽快冷冻他妻子  是吧
Fries has to put his wife on ice as quickly as possible, right?
他不能回家  门口有警察
He can't go home; there's cops at the door.
他会去哪
Where's he gonna go?
他带着设备
He's got the equipment with him.
他可以随便在任何地方冷冻她
He could freeze her anywhere.
等等  他可以冷冻她
Wait. He could freeze her,
但无法保持冷冻状态
but he can't keep her frozen.
必须要用到他建造的冷冻室
Not without one of those cryo chambers he built.
那他的确是要回家
Then he is going home.
冷冻室还在他家
They're still at his house;
没有被收为证据
they were never taken into evidence.
他肯定是去那儿了  走吧
That's where he went, has to be. Come on.
维克多  求你好好想想
Victor, please think about this.
如果你入狱了
How will you take care of her
又要如何照顾她
if you're in prison?
我没法照顾她
I won't.
但你会的
You will.
哥谭会的
Gotham will.
这是法律
It's the law.
只要她在法律意义上还活着  城市就得照顾她
As long as she's legally alive, she's a ward of the city
延续她的生命  保证她的安全
and the city has to keep her alive and safe.
维克多
Victor...
我在  亲爱的
I'm here, darling.
我带你回家了
I brought you home.
我好累
I'm so tired.
我知道
I know.
很快就结束了
It'll all be over soon.
维克多
Victor...
我希望你放手
I want you to let me go.
让我死吧
Let me die.
诺拉  你不是真心的
Nora, you don't mean that.
我能做到  这好使
I can do this. The process works.
好让我有一天醒来
So I shall wake up one day
而你要么在监狱里
with you in prison
要么已经死了吗
or dead?
我并不想要孤独的生活
A life alone isn't one that I want.
你醒来时我会在的  我会的
I'll be there when you wake up. I'll be there.
我会想办法的  我保证
I'll find a way, I will.
希望永远是有的
There's always hope.
只要你活着  就有希望  是吧
As long as you're alive, there's hope, right?
是啊
Yes.
有希望
There's hope.
好吧
Okay.
我的项链
My necklace.
我们一周年纪念时你给我的那条
The one that you gave me on our first anniversary.
在床头柜上
It's on the nightstand.
能去给我拿来吗  亲爱的
Would you get it for me, please, dear?
去吧
Go.
如果有必要  我还有力气用它
I'm strong enough to use it if I need to.
如果你赶快  可以趁他回来之前逃出去
If you hurry, you can make it out before he gets back.
我不会丢下你的
I'm not leaving you.
这对你和你的宝宝一定压力很大
This must be very stressful for you and your baby.
我们没事
We're fine.
能给我点水吗
Could I have some water?
谢谢
Thank you.
你听到了
You heard him.
他内心深处并不坏
He's not a bad man at heart.
你得告诉他们
You have to tell them that.
我会的
I will.
也告诉他们  我对我扮演的角色也很抱歉
And please tell them that I'm very sorry for my part in this.
我看出他要变成什么样
I saw the man that he was becoming
却袖手旁观
and I did nothing.
因为我爱他
Because I loved him.
你明白那感觉  是吧
You know what that's like, don't you?
是的
I do.
谢谢
Thank you.
你真好
You've been very kind.
上帝保佑你和你的宝宝
God bless you and your baby.
诺拉
Nora.
我拿来了
I got it.
I've got it.
维克多
Victor.
我爱你
I love you.
别怪自己
Please don't blame yourself.
我爱你
I love you.
回头见
See you soon.
你最好退后点
You should stand back.
你从窗户进来时我感觉到了风
I felt the breeze when you came in the window.
你来正好
I'm glad you came.
我想请你帮个忙
I need a favor.
"见到你真高兴  塞琳娜"
"Nice to see you, Selina."
抱歉没告诉你我要离开这里
Sorry for not telling you that I was skipping town
跑去我法国的城堡
to go to my castle in France.
只是个小屋
It's a chalet.
是在瑞士
In Switzerland.
随便了
Whatever.
那位英国国王呢
Where's the king of snotty England?
阿尔弗雷德进城了
Alfred went to the city.
茜尔薇说的  就是这个人
This is the man that Silver told us about.
阿尔弗雷德找到了他
Alfred tracked him down.
帕特里克·马龙
Patrick Malone?
他的名字不是M开头的吗
I thought his name started with M.
M是火柴  是外号
The M stands for Matches. It's a nickname.
好二的外号
That's a lame nickname.
你找到他了
So you found him.
你要我做什么
What do you need me for?
我要你给我找把枪
I need you to get me a gun.
你想杀了他吗
So you're gonna kill him?
-对  -你的管家知道吗
- Yes. - Your butler know?
阿尔弗雷德认为他要来杀他
Alfred thinks he's gonna be the one to kill him.
所以我才找你
That's why I'm asking you.
你都做不到把那人推出窗外
You couldn't even push that guy out of the window,
你要怎么做到这个
so how do you expect to do this?
因为这人杀了我父母
Because this man killed my parents.
你以前开过枪吗
You ever even fired a gun before?
求你  塞琳娜  我只能向你...
Please, Selina, you're the only person I can...
你根本不明白你要我做什么  布鲁斯
You don't even know what you're asking, Bruce.
是啊  那人是该死  但你这么做
Yeah, sure, the guy deserves it, but doing this,
你会彻底
you won't ever,
完全地变个人
ever be the same.
我就想那样
That's what I'm counting on.
该死
Crap.
你打算怎么办
How do you want to play this one?
小心慢慢来
Slow and careful.
如果可以  就别动枪
No gun play if we can help it.
拉起警戒线
Set up a perimeter.
我进去看看
I'm gonna look inside.
好的
Gotcha.
拉警戒线
Perimeter.
拉个警戒线
Hey, set up a perimeter.
再稍等我一下  医生
Give me one more moment, Doctor,
然后我就向你自首
then I'll put myself in your charge.
不
No.
不不不
No. No, no. No, no, no.
不不
No, no, no. No!
诺拉
Nora!
我不明白  明明好使的
I don't understand, it works.
我的冷冻液好使的  怎么会
My formula works. How...?!
她换了液罐
She switched cartridges.
She changed the cartridges?
你知道吗
Did you know?
你知道她换掉了吗
Did you know she switched the cartridges?
不
No.
我很遗憾
I'm-I'm so sorry.
弗莱斯先生  我们是哥谭市警局
Mr. Fries, this is the GCPD.
你被包围了
You're surrounded.
请出来  自首吧
Please come out, give yourself up,
别再制造更多痛苦了
and let's avoid any more sadness.
是啊
Yeah.
再没有痛苦了
No more sadness.
能麻烦你
Will you be very kind
去告诉警方  我会照做吗
and go tell the police that I'll do as they say?
诺拉非常爱你
Nora loved you very much.
我很羡慕你们之间的感情
I'm envious of the bond you had.
哥谭市警局
GCPD.
维克多
Victor?
天呐
Oh, my God.
你该继续去睡
You should go back to bed.
睡不着
Can't sleep.
听到你打电话来着
Heard you on the phone.
雨果·斯特兰奇来电
Hugo Strange called.
维克多·弗莱斯死在了阿卡姆的医务室
Victor Fries died in Arkham infirmary.
没抢救过来
They couldn't revive him.
你没事吧
You okay?
没事
I am.
你呢
Are you?
真希望你没去
Wish you hadn't gone.
真希望你没拿我们的孩子冒险
Wish you hadn't put our baby at risk.
是你拿诺拉冒险
You put us at risk
我们才会有危险
when you put Nora at risk.
她是我的病人
She was under my care.
那不一样  那是警察工作
That was different; that was police work.
那是你  都是你的决定
That was you; it's all you.
阿卡姆其实是巴恩斯的主意
Arkham was actually Barnes's idea,
但这合情理
but it made sense.
是聪明的办案手段
It was good police work.
那盖勒文呢
What about Galavan?
也是聪明办案吗
Was that good police work too?
他怎么了
What about him?
他的死状
The way he died.
不管究竟是怎么回事  肯定不是你说的那样
Whatever the truth is, it's not what you told me.
你怎么知道
How do you know?
因为你撒谎我是看得出来的
Because I know when you're being dishonest.
知道吗  如果说有谁该死  那就是盖勒文
And you know what, if anybody deserves to die, it's Galavan.
别跟我说什么警察工作
Don't talk to me about police work.
是你  你对我撒谎
It's you, you lie to me.
我知道你说过没有不可能的案例
I know you say there are no hopeless cases.
的确没有
And there are none.
生命可以在
The beauty of life
最严酷的气候下萌芽生长
can spring forth from even the harshest of climates.
我们只需要
We simply need to be more...
采取更加强效的治疗
aggressive in our treatment.
我得去安顿我们的新客人了
Now I must go see to our newest guest.
早啊  维克多
Good morning, Victor.
我在哪
Where am I?
法律上讲  你的尸体在阿卡姆停尸房里
Legally, your corpse is in the Arkham morgue,
但显然  你是在这儿
but... obviously you're here.
印第安山
Indian Hill.
印第安山是有毒废料填埋场
Indian Hill's a toxic waste dump.
很好用的幌子
A useful fiction.
你是在阿卡姆对我说话的那人
You're the one who spoke to me in Arkham.
雨果·斯特兰奇
Hugo Strange.
很荣幸跟你当面相见
A pleasure to meet you face-to-face.
我怎么还没死
How is it I'm not dead?
简直令人惊叹  是吧
It's simply astonishing, isn't it?
我猜你在这几个月来吸收了一些
My guess is that you absorbed some of your own formula
你制造的冷冻液
over the past months.
你的身体发生了深刻的细胞层面改变
Your body underwent a profound cellular change.
你被带进来时  居然还过热了
When you were brought in here, you were actually overheating.
看那边
Now look there.
温度计
At the thermometer.
零下28度
Negative 20 degrees.
我一点也不冷
And I'm not even cold.
你的冷冻液似乎降低了
Your formula appears to have lowered
你的体核温度
your core body temperature.
你只能在极低温环境下生存
You can only survive in severe hypothermic conditions.
零点之上的温度会要你的命
Anything above freezing will kill you.
别担心  你不会永远被关在里面
But never fear, you won't be locked in there forever.
我们修改了一下你的外衣
We've made some modifications to your suit
让你可以自由走动
to allow you to walk freely.
现在  休息吧
For now, rest.
明天  我们开始工作
Tomorrow we begin work.
有一个项目你会格外感兴趣的
One project in particular I think you'll find fascinating.
我该跟诺拉一起死的
I should have died with Nora.
这一切本该结束的
This all should have ended.
那就把握这个机会吧  维克多
Then take this opportunity, Victor.
假装你已经死了
Pretend you did die.
死亡不是结局
Death is not an ending.
死亡是新的开始
Death is a new beginning.